想當然耳我把時區設定在冰島就因為我們都...
And of course I set it to Icelandic time because we share...
喜歡北極星所發散之極光，高蒂。
a love of the aurora borealis, Gordy.
而妳絕對不知道現在到底是幾點。
And you have no idea how to tell time.
真棒的禮物，爸。
Great gift, Dad.
還真是能掰啊。
Way to think things through.
不知如何，你不覺得一個...
Somehow, you'd think that a man..
能夠把火箭送上太空的人，卻只能夠...
who can send a rocket into space would be able...
準備這種半吊子的生日禮物。
to manage a halfway decent birthday present.
不!
Nope.
高蒂，妳知道嗎，考量到各個層面，
You know, Gordy, all things considered,
也許我準備的禮物並沒有那麼差。
maybe my gift isn't so bad after all.
嘿，高蒂。 想不到吧！
Hey, Gordy. Surprise!
哇喔！ 終於有份像樣的禮物了。
Wow! Now, there's a gift.
高蒂，拆禮物吧。
Here you go, Gordy.
生日快樂。
Happy birthday.
喔，真漂亮，海莉。
Oh, beautiful, Haley.
"我必將可憎汙穢之物拋在你身上，
辱沒你，為眾目所觀。" - 那鴻書 3:6
各位聽眾早安，今天...
Good morning on what is...
肯定是個風勢強勁的日子。
sure to be a windy one.
這波強風警報的範圍...
We have a high wind warning...
從洛杉磯郡海岸線至陜谷區...
for the L.A. County coast and valleys...
雲層將於上午十點左右聚積。
with some clouds sure to come in around 10:00 a.m.
而儘管強風警報，嗯...
And even though the high gust warning will, um, expire
僅由午夜發佈至清晨，聽眾們還是得注意...
mid to late morning, you'll still want to keep...
(幽魂)
關於失蹤登山客的搜救...
The search for a group of missing hikers...
今早將於 阿瓜•杜爾塞 再度進行。
is set to resume this morning just outside Agua Dulce.
兩天前這組觀光旅行團出發前往...
The tour group went out two days ago...
攀登 太平洋屋脊步道...
and on the Pacific Crest Trail...
但並未如期於晚間返回。
but didn't come back as expected that night.
(螢火蟲)
搜救隊於昨日清晨開始進行搜救...
Crews started searching yesterday morning...
而路況已經開始壅塞...
And traffic is already backed up...
肇事主因為南下路段101發生事故。
due to an accident on the southbound 101.
現在時刻是 07:44 波 與 艾維斯 在空中陪伴您。
It is 7:44 with Bo and Ives.
碰！
Bang.
哇。 別這樣。
Whoa. Come on.
躺下，躺下。
Down, down.
躺，躺，躺。
Down, down, down.
碰！ 對了，好孩子。
Bang! Yes, a good boy.
起來。 起，起。
Up. Up, up.
好了，起來。起，起。
Okay, up. Up, up.
隨時都得抬頭注意天氣的變化。
Got to keep our heads up out the clouds on this one.
我知道。
I know.
現在，我們駐足在這兒...
Now, we land this...
是呀。就像「六發左輪」一樣。
Yeah. Like Six Guns.
我的意思是，我們真的做得有聲有色，
I mean, we really put on a show,
你知道電影公司將請我們參與續集演出嗎？
well, you know they're gonna bring us back for the sequel.
嗯哼。
Mm-hmm.
這樣一來我們可不能再賣任何一匹馬了。
Well, we sure as hell ain't got to sell no more horses.
所以我們就好好幹吧。
So just execute.
而我們就不會再有其他狀況了。嗯。
And we ain't got no more problems. Mm.
你辦得到嗎？
You good?
你行嗎？
你妹去哪裡了？
Where your sister?
又去做什麼了？
What's that about?
她應該在這裡才對。 是啊。
She's supposed to be here. Yeah.
真該死。
Goddamn it.
我不是跟你說過把該死的踱步機修好嗎。
Thought I told you to fix the damn walker.
你聽到了嗎？
You hear that?
爸。
Pops.
撐著點，撐著點，爸。 螢火蟲。
Come on, come on. Pop. Firefly.
還有什麼？還有什麼？ 幽魂。
What else? What else?  Ghost.
還有哩。
Uh-huh.
貝多芬。
Beethoven.
對了，對了。
Uh-huh, uh-huh.
艦長。 對。
Commodore. Yeah.
維吉爾。
Virgil.
你還好。你還好。
You good. You good.
你還撐得下去。你可以的。
你沒事的，爸。你還好。
You good, man. You good.
幽魂。你還可以。你還可以。你還可以。
Ghost. You good. You good. You good.
爸？ 吉利。
Pops? Lucky.
爸。爸。 艦長。
Pops. Pops. Commodore.
爸！
Pops!
[不]
歐傑。
OJ.
喔。嗨，小馬。
Oh. Hi, horsie.
嘿，嘿，嘿。請不要直接跟他直接對上眼。
Hey, hey, hey. Don't look him in the eyes, please.
好吧。
Okay.
你準備好開始勤前安全教育了嗎？
You ready to do the safety meeting?
嗯，我可能需要五分...
Uh, I'm gonna need like five...
嗯，我的組員快到了。
Um, my team's almost here.
你們團隊還沒到齊。
Your team's not here.
好吧。 先待著。
Okay. Hold.
抱歉，我也正跟馴馬師溝通中。
Sorry, I got the horse guy talking to me, too.
怎麼了？ 了解。 勤前安全教育將於...
What's up? Copy. Safety meeting at the...
女士與先生們，邦妮·克萊頓 女士蒞臨片場。
Ladies and gentlemen, Ms. Bonnie Clayton on set.
各位，她在這裡。
Here she is, everybody.
看看這身造型。
Take a look at all of that.
芬恩，這位是 歐傑，我們的馴馬師。
Fynn, this is OJ, our horse trainer.
你記得那些從片場來的人嗎？
You remember these guys from Flash Point.
記得。 嗨。
Yeah. Hi.
哦...
Uh...
你的名字叫 歐傑？
Your name is OJ?
是的，歐提斯二世。
Yeah, Otis Junior.
喔。
Oh.
哦...
Uh...
那個老...另一個傢伙哩？
Where's the o... the other guy?
另...另...另一個年長的？ 老兄，他過世了。
The-the-the senior guy? Dude, he died.
六個月前左右。
About six months ago.
被一堆從飛機上掉下來的雜物給砸死。
A bunch of random shit fell out of a plane.
所以，我覺得我們得將就點跟二代配合了。
So I guess we're stuck with Junior over here.
不。 是呀。
No. Yeah.
好吧。
Okay.
幹。 好極了。
Fuck. Great.
哦，安特，拍起來感覺如何？
Uh, Ant, how we looking?
嗯，不錯啊，如果我們要拍的是馬屁的話。
Yeah, good, if we're selling a horse's ass.
這位是，嗯，
That's, uh,
這邊這位是傳奇攝影師 安特勒斯·霍爾斯特...
legendary cinematographer Antlers Holst over here...
讓馬兒轉個圈，我們繼續拍吧。
Let's go ahead and spin the horse.
但是你剛剛說：站著，所以...
But you had said "hold," so...
而我現在說：轉圈。 快點。
And now I'm saying "spin." Let's go.
好極了。 在馬兒旋轉的同時，我們來搞定髮妝？
Great. And while that's spinning, can we get makeup?
請化妝師幫 邦妮·克萊頓 女士搞定髮妝。
Get makeup for Ms. Bonnie Clayton, please.
等等。
Hold on.
可以請你們離馬遠一點嗎？
Can you step away from the back, please?
片組人員叫我們來這裡。
They told me to come here.
做得好，歐傑。 嗯，這樣好了，
Good call, OJ. Um, tell you what,
我們來快速宣導一下勤前安全教育。
let's do a quick safety meeting.
各位。這位是 歐傑，我們的馴馬師。
Guys, this is OJ, our horse trainer.
交給你了。
Take it away.
請關掉音樂。
Kill the music, please.
我叫 歐傑。嗯...
My name is OJ. Uh...
我覺得我妹就快到了。
I think my sister's gonna be here in a minute.
請大聲點。 我們後面根本聽不到。
Little louder, please. We cannot hear you in the back.
我們稱做：動物培育師...
I said we are animal wranglers...
來自海伍德好萊塢馬場。
with Haywood Hollywood Horses.
而，哦...你們知道最早的，嗯，組...
And, uh... did you know the very first, uh, assem...
嘿，大家好！
Hey, yo!
不好意思。 抱歉。
Excuse me. Sorry.
抱歉撞到妳了。 換我來講吧。
I'm so sorry about that. Let me do that.
抱歉了，老哥。
Sorry, brother.
勤前安全教育。 是的。
Safety meeting. Yeah.
哈囉！ 大家好嗎？
Hello! How y'all doing?
很抱歉來晚了。
Sorry for the tardiness.
我叫 安莫洛，這位是 歐傑，
My name is Emerald, that's OJ,
而我們是你們今天的動物培育師
and we are your animal wranglers today
來自海伍德好萊塢馬場。
with Haywood Hollywood Horses.
你們大家知道最早...
Now, did you know that the very first...
將照片按照順序排列...
assembly of photographs in sequential order...
所組成的動畫...
to create a motion picture...
是一部二秒鐘黑人騎馬的短片嗎？
was a two-second clip of a Black man on a horse?
是的，事實如此。是的，事實如此。可以去查一下。
Yes, it was. Yes, it was. Look it up.
我知道你們都認識 埃德沃德·邁布里奇，
Now, I know you guys know Eadweard Muybridge,
這位動畫影片鼻祖...
the grandfather of motion pictures...
是這部動畫短片的創作者，
who took the pictures that created that clip,
但有人知道這位在馬背上...
but does anybody know the name of the Black jockey...
黑人騎師是誰嗎？
that rode the horse?
不。
No.
沒人？ 我說，這名首位特技演員，
Nope? I mean, the very first stuntman,
動物培訓員及電影明星集於一身，
animal wrangler and movie star all rolled into one,
而卻誇張地沒有任他的任何紀錄。
and there is literally no record of him.
這名來自巴哈馬的騎師...
That man was a Bahamian jockey...
就叫做 阿利斯泰爾·E·海伍德。
that went by the name of Alistair E. Haywood.
而他就是我的曾曾祖父。
And he is my great-great-grandfather.
棒極了。 那裡還有另一個 "曾" 祖父。
Great.  There's another "great" grandfather.
這也是我為何回到 海伍德 馬場，
That's why back at the Haywood Ranch,
好萊塢唯一由黑人經營的訓馬場，
as the only Black-owned horse trainers in Hollywood,
我們喜歡這樣說："自圖片開始會動的那一刻起，
we like to say, "Since the moment pictures could move,
我們就參與其中。"
we had skin in the game."
好了，讓我們進入，嗯，安全防護...
All right, let's get into some, uh, safety precautions...
趁大家都在片場的時候，好嗎？
while we're on set, shall we?
規則一，請避免產生任何巨大的聲響，
Number one, please refrain from making any loud noises,
突然的大動作，以及保持手機關機。
sudden movements, and keep your cell phones off.
我們將感激不盡您的合作。
We'd really appreciate that.
規則二，如果您看到任何讓您覺得不安全的事物，
Two, if you see anything that looks or feels unsafe,
聯絡我、歐傑或任何相關職務代理人。
contact me, OJ or your second in chain of command.
規則三，讓我們來開拍吧！
And three, let's have a great shoot!
嗯，而我叫 安莫洛·海沃。
Uh, and I'm Emerald Haywood.
我能導，能寫、能製，能演。
I direct, write, produce, act.
我還可以做...
I do a little...
哦，摩托車特技，寶貝。
Uh, motorcycles, baby.
聽著，我...我還會烤些乳酪薄餅...
Look, I-I make a mean grilled cheese...
如果你們正在找全方位的助手的話。
if you're looking for crafty.
就...就聯絡我吧。
Just-just holler at me.
好的，很棒的介紹。
Okay, that was great.
這真是...這真是豐富。
That was... that was a lot.
嗯，讓我們開始排演吧。
Uh, let's do a rehearsal.
好了？ 排演？ 我們應該開始排演了。
Yeah? Rehearsal? Rehearsing, we should.
我們應該來排一場。 演練一下。
We should do one. Rehearsing.
我覺得...我可能得休息片刻。
I think... I think he might need a break.
好啊，我們先來排練一場，
Yeah, we'll rehearse one first,
接著再休息，好嗎？
and then break, yeah?
好的，我準備好來排演一場了。
Well, I'm ready to do one.
歐傑，她...她已經準備好要排演了。
OJ, she's...she's ready to do one.
跟馬說一下我們準備要來排演了。
Tell the horse we're ready to do one.
視效組，當我們入場時可以把球擺在這裡嗎？
VFX, can we get the ball in here while we have a sec?
安。 視效組。 嗯，還有 歐傑，
Em. VFX. Uh, and, OJ,
你可以...你可以下來了。
you can... you can step off.
站出去。 下來。
Step out. Step off.
好，好的。 哦，站出來。
Yeah, yeah.  Uh, step out.
安？
Em?
這匹馬叫什麼名字？
What's the horse's name?
哦，吉利。 叫 吉利 啊。
Uh, Lucky. Lucky.
是公的？ 視效組。
Is he?  VFX!
是的。 安？
Yeah. Em?
嗯，歐傑，我們站出來吧。 你叫我？
Uh, OJ, let's step off.  You calling me?
嘿，嘿，嘿，嘿，嘿，嘿。 我試著要工作。
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.  I'm trying to work.
老兄，我是怎麼告訴你的？
What'd I tell you about that, man?
嘿，老兄，如果她沒辦法靠近這匹馬，
Hey, man, if she can't get near the back of the horse,
那我們在這裡搞啥？ 嘿，嘿，嘿，嘿！
what are we doing here?  Hey, hey, hey, hey!
喔！  喔，喔，喔，喔，喔，
Whoa!  Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa,
喔，喔，喔，喔，喔，喔。  醫護組。
whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.  Medic.
喔，喔，喔，喔。
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
你還好嗎？  喔，喔。
Are you okay?  Whoa, whoa.
聽著，也許回片場工作還太早，是吧？
Look, maybe it's just too soon, huh?
是啊，不是演出的問題。 是還沒準備好。
Yeah, it's not the gig. Not ready yet.
是吧？
Right?
我們需要這份工作，老兄。  不，我了解。
We need it, man.  No, I know.
你們父親留下了一個巨大的財務缺口。 我知道這件事。
Your dad left an enormous hole.  I know that.
不過別擔心，還有其它機會的。
But don't worry, there'll be others.
還好嗎？ 我很抱歉。
All right? I'm sorry.
而且...  抱歉。
And...   Sorry.
就，你跟她說不好意思。
Just, you tell her sorry.
謝謝你給我們這個機會。
Thank you for the opportunity.
別這麼客氣了。
Come on, now.
喔，視效組哪去了？
Oh, where's VFX?
喔，準備好了。 視效組來了。
Oh, all right. You got it.
抱歉，剛剛真是...
Sorry, that was...
所以，我要載妳到哪裡？
So, where am I dropping you?
我要跟著你。
I'm-a go up with you.
我得回家拿點東西。
I need to get some shit.
我的姊妹說，我可以過去她那邊擠一擠，
My little girl said, you know, I could crash at her place,
所以我大概明早就離開。
so I'll be gone in the morning.
所以我明天還得載妳回去？
So I'm gonna drive you back tomorrow?
我可以找便車搭。
I can find a ride.
但我想說的是，這個雞雞歪歪的 歐傑 可以振作一下嗎？
But, I mean, like, can I get fun OJ out this bitch?
因為這個機歪 歐傑...
'Cause this wack-ass OJ...
真的讓我感受不到一點兄妹之情。
is really making me feel like I'm not loved.
這就是你想讓你小妹感受的氛圍？
Is that how you want your little sister to feel?
黃金夢 這區怎麼了？
What happened to Gold Rush?
黃金夢 這區破產了。
Gold Rush went bankrupt.
這樣子已經持續三年了。
It's been this for three years.
該死。 旅人們，您好。
Damn.  Howdy, folks.
歡迎來到 朱比特礦場。
Welcome to Jupiter's Claim.
站上前來許願池。
Step on up for the wishing well.
抽獎送碎花長裙。
Get your Jupe Jangle.
來吧，來水井旁拍照。
Go on, take a picture at the well.
男女牛仔們，
Cowboys and cowgirls,
請注意。
just a little heads-up.
參加我們週五下午五點半全新登場的...
Join us Fridays at 5:30 p.m. for the brand-spanking-new...
朱比特礦場星空牛仔特技秀。
Jupiter's Claim Star Lasso Experience.
這裡有好吃的冰淇淋聖代。
Come on over to the Sundae Saloon.
快來喝沁心冰涼的沙士。
Get your ice-cold sarsaparilla.
快看這個。 我從沒看過像這樣的東西。
Look at this. I've never seen anything like it.
哦，該死... 搞什麼鬼。
Oh, shi...  Come on.
大夥們，不好意思。 我很抱歉。
I'm sorry, y'all. I'm sorry.
不小心亂入了。 被妳毀了啦。
Photo bomb.  You ruined it.
是呀，是我不對。 我跟妳說，是金子啊。
Yeah, my bad.  Gold, I tell you.
坑裡都是金子啊。
They got gold up in here.
吉利。
Lucky.
好好待著。
Hang tight.
我馬上回來。
I'll be back.
我們走吧。
Let's go.
你賣掉多少了？
How many you sold?
多少？
How many?
十匹。
Ten.
你賣掉爸的十匹馬？
You sold ten of Pops' horses?
我會贖牠們回來的。
I'm gonna get 'em back.
妳能待在這裡嗎？  為什麼？
Can you stay out here?   Why?
我正拓展一個商業聯盟，
I'm developing a business relationship,
而妳現在是個累贅。
and you're a liability right now.
怎麼我變成累贅了？
How am I a liability?
妳怎麼不是個累...
How are you a lia...
不要再推銷妳那該死的斜槓技能了。
Don't promote your fucking side shit on the job.
喔，我的天啊。 演員、歌手、舞者、
Oh, my God.  Actor, singer, dancer,
服裝設計、機車特技。
seamstress, motorcycles.
妳如果真要推銷，就專注在商業合作上。
You want to promote something, promote this business.
不，歐傑。 不是這樣。
No, OJ. No.
首先，這才不是啥斜槓雜技。 訓馬才是。
First of all, that's not my side shit. This is.
再來，如果說誰是累贅...
And second of all, if anybody's a liability...
幹林娘。 不，幹林娘。
Fuck you.  No, fuck you.
您們好。  又是我，朱比特礦場的安柏。
Hi there. It's Amber again from Jupe's Claim.
看來我們還能再擠出些，哦，
It does look like we were able to squeeze out, uh,
幾張額外的媒體公關票...
a couple of extra press passes...
讓您的朋友、家人們參加首映。
for the upcoming friends and family preview.
喔。 沒有道歉的必要。
Oh. No apology necessary.
這是這座樂園有史以來最具規模、最大型，
This is in reference to the biggest, bestest,
且嶄新推出的實境秀，
brand-new live show we have coming up here at the park,
已經悄悄準備就緒了...  請進。
which is sneaking up on us...   Come in.
如果你們喜歡的話，我可以幫你們安排到...
If you'd like, I can go ahead and put you down...
歐傑。
OJ.
感謝過來一趟。
Thanks for coming up.
過得怎樣？  這是我妹妹 安。
How you doing?  This is my sister Em.
妳好。
Hi there.
所以，哦...你這次帶誰給我？
So, uh... who'd you bring me?
哦，吉利。
Uh, Lucky.
牠是我第二傑出的馬，不過，哦...
He's my second-best horse, you know, uh...
牠有些力不從心。
He lost focus.
所以，哦...我的意思是，我也是，不過我總不能開除我自己吧。
So, uh... I mean, I did, too, but I can't fire myself.
沒關係。  等一下。
That's good.  Hold up.
這是你？
This you?
你是「小鬼警長」裡的亞洲男孩本人？
You literally the Asian kid from Kid Sheriff?
安，安，安，安...    不，沒關係。
Em, Em, Em, Em...   No, it's okay.
是呀，我曾是，哦...我曾是 李朱佩。
Yeah, I was, uh... I was Lil' Jupe.
啊，老兄，你可曾經是我最愛的角色。
Ah, dude, you were literally my favorite.
你介意我快速地拍張照嗎？
You mind if I get a picture real quick?
嘿，妳沒看到我們正在談事情嗎？
Hey, you mind if we talk?
是的。 好吧。
Yes. Of course.
請隨便參觀吧。
Please, browse away.
我家就是妳家。
Su casa es mi casa.
謝謝你。 我會好好參觀。
Thank you. I sure will.
嗯，所以...
Um, so...
價錢一樣，對吧？ 11萬5千 ?
same deal, yeah? Eleven-five?
是的。 謝謝你。     這是立體的。 是呀。
Yeah. Thank you.   That's 3D. Yeah.
那個黑人男孩後來怎樣了？  他演得超好的。
Whatever happened to that Black boy? He was good.
好了，別說了。
Stop, stop.
他很會演。
He was good.
我其實想要，哦，談點基本條款，
I actually wanted to, uh, lay some groundwork,
哦，一些方...方式，哦，可以贖回牠們的條款。
uh, to a pathway of-of, uh, buying some of them back.
可以嗎？
All right?
好呀。 嗯哼。
Yeah.   Mm-hmm.
可呀。完全同意。
Yeah. Totally.
嗯...
Um...
好的。 好？
Yeah.   Yeah?
事實上，歐傑，
Actually, OJ,
我開給你父親的協議依然有效。
the offer I made your dad is still on the table.
喔，哦...
Oh, uh...
讓我...讓...         呦，等一下下。
Let me... Let...   Yo, wait a minute.
所以，這...
So, that...
歐傑，我讓你看過這個嗎？
OJ, have I shown you this?
這些是高蒂之家事故的遺物。
This is in reference to the Gordy's Home incident.
高蒂之家。  是呀，是的。
Gordy's Home. Yeah, yeah.
高蒂之家是部虛構的直播情境短劇...
So, Gordy's Home is a short-lived but fabled sitcom...
小鬼警長停播後，我在96年加入這齣戲。
I starred in in '96 after Kid Sheriff blew up.
我知道，我爸跟我說過這部戲。
Yeah, my pops told me about this show.
就...就猴子突然發瘋不受控制什麼的。
The-the monkey went crazy or some shit.
你們知道嗎，參觀的話我通常是收費的。
You know, I usually charge a fee for this.
喔，真屌。
Oh, damn.
請進。
Ta-da.
嗯~~~
Hmm.
這可是我們首次 "頂拳" 的照片。
That's the first exploding fist bump.
什麼？ 真的假的？
What? Really?
這就是整部戲的源起？
Y'all came up with that?
誠如我剛說的，哦，高蒂之家播出始於...
So, as I was saying, uh, Gordy's Home began airing...
96年的秋季...
in the fall of '96...
而這部戲馬上就紅了。
...and it was an immediate hit.
嗯，迴響十分踴躍。
Uh, ratings were huge.
評價極佳。
Pretty good reviews.
收視率竄升。
Just really took off.
是喔。
Yeah.
接著，哦，有一天...
Then, uh, one day...
我們正在拍其中一集...
...we were shooting an episode
嗯，第二季一集叫「高蒂的生日」。
in season two entitled, uh, "Gordy's Birthday."
接著，嗯...碰。
And, um... boom.
其中一隻演 高蒂 的猩猩就...
One of the chimps that plays Gordy just...
突然就不受控制。
just hit his limit.
而這場浩劫一共持續了六分十三秒。
And it was six minutes and 13 seconds of havoc.
電視臺嘗試淡化與論，但這齣戲可是直播情境劇。
Network tried to bury hit, but it was a spectacle.
觀眾們非常癡迷。
People are just obsessed.
你沒開玩笑吧。
You're kidding me.
歐傑，你曾說你知道這件事？
OJ, you said you heard about that?
對啊。這就是為何他們不允許讓猩猩演出。
Mm-hmm. That's why they don't let you use chimps.
原因有部份跟這件事有關。
That's part of the reason.
高蒂之家的粉絲正逐漸增長中。
There's a growing Gordy's Home fan base out there now.
有對荷蘭夫妻付我五萬塊...
This Dutch couple paid me 50K
就為了來這裡過夜。
to come in here and spend the night.
我沒過問。
I didn't ask.
這真瘋狂。
That's crazy.
老兄，所以究竟發生過什麼事？
So, what happened really, man?
妳沒看過 SNL 裡壞高蒂的短劇嗎？
You haven't seen the Bad Gordy sketch on SNL?
要我來說，裡頭演的可比我說的還要來得接近實況。
I mean, they pretty much nailed it better than I could.
什麼。 沒聽過？
Mm.  No?
週六夜現場？
Saturday Night Live?
達雷爾·哈蒙德 演的 湯姆。
Darrell Hammond as Tom.
安娜·加斯泰爾 演 菲利斯。
Ana Gasteyer as Phyllis.
切里奧特里 演 瑪麗·喬·艾略特。
Cheri Oteri as Mary Jo Elliot.
史考特·沃爾夫 是該集主持。 他扮演我。
Scott Wolf is the host.   He's me.
不過，這部短劇的主角...
But, of course, the star of the sketch
就是那該死的 克里斯·卡坦 所演的 高蒂，
is Chris goddamn Kattan as Gordy,
而他簡直是...
and he is...
不可置否，好嗎。
undeniable, okay?
劇情大致上是這樣。
Bit goes like this.
大夥們準備幫 高蒂 慶生，
Everyone's trying to celebrate Gordy's birthday,
但每次 高蒂 聽到叢林相關的詞彙，
but every time Gordy hears something about the jungle,
高蒂...    卡坦...   就爆發了。
Gordy... Kattan... goes off.
而這...這可是卡坦啊。
And it's... it's Kattan.
他演得栩栩如生。
He's just crushing it.
他宛如角色上身。
He is a force of nature.
他在舞臺上大殺四方。
He is killing on that stage.
是的。
Yeah.
簡直是傳奇。
It's legendary.
經典的短劇。
Legendary shit.
是呀。
Yeah.
好的，我決定直接找找，
Yeah, I'm gonna have to go ahead,
YouTube 上面的影片。
look that one up on YouTube.
好好地仔細看一下。
Details, you know?
應該的。
Totally.
我還有些工作得做。
I got some work I got to do.
所以我們今晚沒得鬆一下，什麼節目都沒有？
So we ain't gonna chill tonight, nothing?
不然妳要做？  當然不。
You want to work?   Hell no.
所以，哦，那協議是啥？
So, uh, what was the offer?
朱佩 嗎？ 是的。
Jupe?   Yeah.
他想買下牧場。
He offered to buy the ranch.
喔，真假？
Oh, really?
這可有趣了。  開價多少？
That's interesting. How much?
想知道？
Why?
因為... 我總得看看你愚蠢的極限值在哪裡。
'Cause... I'm trying to see how big of a dumbass you are.
也許蠢到爆表也說不定。
Big dumbass, probably.
所以我猜你不想知道有什麼好貨...
So I guess you don't want to see what's good...
在老爸的酒櫃裡了吧？
with Dad liquor cabinet, then, huh?
事實上，除了酒，我還有娛樂大麻。
I got that hobby weed, too, actually.
你剛剛這樣說不就好了。
That's all you had to say, then.
娛樂大麻。
The hobby weed.
你這樣說就對了，讓我知道一下。
That's all you had to say, just let me know.
你應該一開始就跟我說的。
You should've dropped that at the top.
"我手頭有娛樂大麻"。 你知道我隨時準備好的。
"I got the hobby weed." You know I'm ready.
好吧，你的反射動作依然很快啊。 就像毫無遲疑一樣。
Okay, your reflexes are still quick. Like, whoa.
我又沒生氣。   我看著喔。
I ain't mad at it.   I'm watching.
敬爸一杯。
To the man.
喝啊。
Drink.
喔，該死。
Oh, shit.
記得 牛仔外套 嗎？
Remember Jean Jacket?
記得，是匹好馬。
Yeah, good horse.
其實，這應該是我第一匹馬。
Supposed to be my first horse, actually.
我才剛跟我的心理治療師談到這件事...
I was just talking to my therapist about this...
不久前而已。        治療師？
not too long ago.   Therapist?
是的。 我偶爾也會來一砲的那種。
Yes. I fuck one on occasion sometimes.
我才跟她聊過這件事，九歲生日的事，
I was telling her that, for my ninth birthday,
我本該有機會去培訓 牛仔外套 的。
I was supposed to get to train Jean Jacket.
但爸接了些西部片拍，而...
But then Pops got some Western, and...
牛仔外套 就再也不屬於我了。
Jean Jacket wasn't mine no more.
老 歐提斯 常幹的事。
Classic Otis Senior.
這事彷彿還歷歷在目...
I distinctly remember...
我站在這扇窗前，
...standing right here at this window,
看著你們培訓我的馬。
watching y'all train my horse.
我的馬。
My horse.
爸從沒抬頭看我一眼。
Pops never looked up at me.
歐傑，過來。
OJ, come on.
但，老哥你會。
But you did, nigga.
記得嗎？
Remember?
事實上，那部片是魔蠍大帝。
It was Scorpion King, actually.
根本不是西部片。
It wasn't a Western.
這也是爸第一次帶著我去拍的片。
That was the first job Pops took me on.
那時可沒那麼好玩。
Wasn't much fun.
結果後來還是用駱駝拍，所以...
Ended up using camels anyways, so...
重點是...
The point is...
嘖，幹她媽的重點。
Yeah, fuck the point.
呦，這個人就是幹她媽的頑固。
Yo, that man was hardheaded as fuck.
而妳也是。
And so are you.
就是這樣子。
That's it.
但就環顧他一生經歷來說，你不得不...
But at the end of the day, you got to...
你不得不承認，爸這個人...
you got to admit, man, Pops...
爸為了成就這個地方付出了許多心血。
Pops did something when he made this place.
他改變了這個產業。
He changed the industry.
這倒是真的。
That's real.
我不能讓這事業付之東流。
I can't just let that go.
幽魂 在訓馬場上幹嘛？
Why is Ghost in the arena?
[幽魂]
什麼那麼好看？
What's good?
Yeah.
嘿，呦，安。安！
Hey, yo, Em. Em!
小聲點！
Turn it down!
好啦！
All right!
嘿！
Hey!
牠要去哪裡？
Where he going?
如果我...
What if I...
如果我告訴你們...
What if I told you...
你們將脫胎換骨般地離開這裡？
...you'll leave here different?
你們知道嗎，過去半年來的每週五...
See, every Friday for the last six months...
我和家人們不厭其煩地見證了...
...my family and I bore witness
一個絕對的...
to an absolute
奇觀。
spectacle.
蛤？
Huh?
你看到了嗎？ 斷電了？
You see it? The power?
幽魂去哪裡了？
Where's Ghost?
我不知道。  等等。
I don't know.  Hold on.
碰。  斷電了。
Boom. Power went out.
看到了嗎？  倒帶。
See?  Rewind.
停。
Stop.
幽魂說道："我才不想聽，
Ghost talking about, "I ain't listening.
我不想訓練，我只幹我想幹的。"
I'm not trained. I do whatever the fuck I want."
怎麼了？
What?
你看到了什麼？
What'd you see?
什麼是 窳劣的奇蹟 ？
What's a bad miracle?
知道嗎？
Hmm?
有任何字眼可以形容嗎？
They got a word for that?
沒！
Nope.
他們說導致爸過世的是螺旋槳飛機還是其他未知因素。
They said it was a prop plane or something that killed Pops.
這鳥事對我來說一點道理也沒有。
That shit ain't never made sense to me.
接著今晚，我聽到幽魂發出聲響...
Then tonight, I heard Ghost make a sound...
一種我從沒聽過馬發出的聲響。
I ain't never heard a horse make.
你看見了什麼？ 說啊？
What did you see? Hmm?
非常大。
It was big.
有多大？  超大。
How big?   Big.
看上去是什麼樣子？  我不知道。
What'd it look like?   I don't know.
速度極快。
It was fast.
太快了。
Too fast.
飛機也沒這麼安靜。
Too quiet to be a plane.
歐傑。
OJ.
你說的是我心理想的那種東西嗎？
Are you saying what I think you're saying?
我告訴你，哥，我們不必買太多東西。
I'm telling you, man, we don't need a lot.
我們只需要準備剛好有辦法拍出...
We just need enough to make our shit...
跟其他人不一樣影片的設備就好。
look different from what's out there.
你明白我在說什麼嗎？  像是...
You get what I'm saying?  Like...
你知道我在準備些什麼吧。
You know I ain't trying to run it up.
我就上網查了一下，而我可是看到了一堆狗屁倒灶的東西。
I just was looking online, and I seen a lot of shit.
你知道我破產了吧？
You know I'm broke, right?
我們用我的錢。
We'll use my money.
好了，閉嘴。  聽著。
Okay, shut up. Look.
好了。
All right.
這就是了。 五千到十幾萬塊。
There it is. Five to a hundred K.
好，看一下。  閱讀障礙白癡，看這裡寫的。
Well, read it.   You read it, dyslexic ass.
重點像是 數位領主 這種網站...
The point is a website like Cyber Dominion...
願意花五千到十幾萬塊...
will pay five to a hundred K...
購買關於幽浮和其他神秘事件的圖像實證。
for photographic evidence of UFOs and shit.
十幾萬？
A hundred K?
而這只是我看到網站時的想法。
And that's just what I saw on the first go.
現在我想了一想，幹牠媽的 數位領主。
Now that I'm thinking about it, fuck Cyber Dominion.
這窳劣的奇蹟是個契機...我們的契機。
This shit right here is a moment... our moment.
我們準備好，在適當的時機釋出，
We set it up, release it the right way,
老哥，我講得可是一輩子的榮華富貴。
man, I'm talking rich and famous for life.
妳好呀！ 妳真漂亮。
How you doing? You look pretty.
她看起來就像是住在豪宅裡的樣子。
She look like she got a big house.
怎麼做？ 什麼？ 我們怎麼釋出嗎？
How?   How what? How we put it out?
嗯。 這，就是我正在講的。
Mm.  Well, that's what I'm saying.
我們缺的可不只一些救急的現金，對吧？
We don't just go for the quick cash-in, okay?
我們...我們得上最具公信力的平臺來講這個故事。
We-we go to the most credible platform to do the story.
那是啥？ 像是 歐普拉·溫芙瑞秀？ 對。
What's that? Like Oprah?        Yeah.
歐普拉·溫芙瑞秀 算是。 播出之後，所有人都想參與。
Like Oprah, for example.  After that, everybody want in.
好吧，我想說的是已經有一堆在...
Well, I'm saying there's plenty...
網路上關於不明飛行物的狗屁影片了。
of videos of flying shit online.
我哪天才在電視上看到而已。 不是在 歐普拉。
I saw one the other day. That wasn't on Oprah.
老哥，我可沒說 歐普拉。 是你說 歐普拉 的。
Nigga, I didn't say Oprah. You said Oprah.
你愛看 歐普拉。
You love Oprah.
聽著，要我說的話網路上那些狗屁全都是假的。
Look, all I'm saying is all that shit online is fake.
低劣畫質。 沒有人可以拍到我們要拍的。
Low quality. Ain't nobody gonna get what we gonna get.
我們拍到什麼？
What we gonna get?
影片啊。  什麼影片？
The shot.   What shot?
賺錢的影片。 這種影片。
The shot. The money shot.
不可置否，奇異非凡，這...
Undeniable, singular, the...
跟 歐普拉 一樣。 歐普拉 的影片？
the Oprah shot.  The Oprah shot?
不好意思。
Excuse me.
嗨。 我這邊可以為您服務。
Hi. I can help you over here.
嗨。
Hi.
感謝您到 福來商城 消費。
Thank you for shopping at Fry's.
你們今天有找到你們想要的商品了嗎？
Did you guys find everything you're looking for today?
是的...安傑。
Yes... Angel.
喔。 好極了。
Oh. Great.
哦，你們有我們的會員卡嗎？
Um, actually, do you have a card with us?
沒，謝謝你。
No, thank you.
嗯，你們想申辦嗎？
Uh, would you like one?
因為會員卡可... 不，謝謝你。
Because it...   No, thank you.
你們有需要我們的技術人員...
Would you like one of our tech support personnel
協助你們安裝設定嗎？
to help you with the installation?
不，不，不，不，不，謝謝你。
No, no, no, no, no, thank you.
感謝您。
Appreciate you.
好吧，嗯，不需要安裝設定服務。
All right, uh, no help with the install.
你們自理。
Suit yourself.
這會很難安裝嗎？
Is it a hard install?
這樣說，對我來說不會。
Well, for me, no.
你們的話應該沒辦法安裝。
You're not gonna be able to do it.
發生什麼事了？ 你們被搶劫了嗎？
What happened? Did you guys get robbed?
是呀。 是呀，你知道的。
Mm-hmm.  Yeah, you know.
一天到晚在停電。
A lot of blackouts.
三不五時攝影機就會沒用。
Take the camera out from time to time.
這些新型的攝影機，有著備用電源，
All these new cameras, they have backup battery power,
應該不會再因斷電而沒作用。
so you should be fine.
但停電不也是會讓電池沒電嗎，
But the outages affect the power in the battery shit, too,
就像手機一樣。
like cell phones.
好吧。 是這樣的。
Okay. All right.
手機，不會瞬間就喪失所有電力好嗎。
Cell phones, they don't just drop in power. Right?
我覺得，也許你們的無線網路會斷線...
I mean, maybe your Wi-Fi drops out...
當你們的系統沒電力時。
whenever your system dips.
所以，這就是科技。
So, that's technology.
好吧，又或者你們剛好住在幽浮熱區。
Okay, or maybe you're in a UFO hot spot.
沒人會信那種東西。
No one believes in that.
還好嗎？
What's up?
該死。 沒注意到你們竟然住那麼遠。
Damn. Did not realize you guys were this far out.
是啊。
Mm-hmm.
我是無所謂啦。
I don't mind, though.
感受一下馬糞跟新鮮空氣的氣息。
Smell of horse shit and fresh air.
是吧？
Right?
啊~~~~~~~~~~~！
Ahhhhhhhhhhhh！
喔，喔，喔。
whoa, whoa, whoa.
喔。 看著我，老兄。
Whoa. Look at me, man.
幹。 別那樣做。 不要鬼叫。
Fuck.   Don't do that. Don't yell.
不好意思，老兄。
Sorry, man.
我為剛剛的行為道歉，今天早上我就像是當了機一樣。
Sorry if I was, like, a little shut down this morning.
我剛結束一段四年的感情。
Just got out of a four-year relationship.
你沒事的。
You were fine.
我知道這幹她媽聽起來很老套。
I know it's gonna sound fucking cliché, all right,
你知道嗎，可是我真的認為她就是我的天命真女。
but I thought that she was the one, you know?
安裝設定會超過一小時嗎？
Is this gonna take longer than an hour?
安裝嗎？ 喔，該死，會喔。
This? Oh, shit, yeah.
那我要出去晃一下囉。 妳要去哪裡？
I'm-a go ahead and pop out.  Where you going?
我得去商店買點東西。
I got to go to the store and get something.
不用管我。 你要買什麼嗎？
Don't worry about it. You need anything?
你看。
Yo.
她的名字叫，嗯，麗貝卡·迪亞茲。
Her name was, uh, Rebecca Diaz.
是呀，我還是有在追蹤她。
Yep, keep an eye out for her.
你知道嗎，她是個演員、模特兒。
She's an actress, model, you know?
CW電視臺找她去演齣試播劇，所以就...
She booked a pilot on The CW, so...
就幹她媽的離開我。
Yeah, fucking left me.
幹她媽的CW電視臺。
Yeah, fucking CW.
所以，關於這臺攝影機... 可以往上旋轉嗎？
So, thing about this camera...   Actually, can it swivel up?
喔，可以。
Uh, yeah.
好了。 能再往上嗎？
Boom.  Little more?
往上。 好的。
More. Okay.
好了。
Yeah.
再往上。
Mm.
嗯，好。
Uh, yeah.
可以。
Mm-hmm.
你知道政府再也不把它們稱作幽浮了嗎？
Do you know they don't call 'em UFOs anymore?
幹，現在叫 "不明空中現象"。
It's fucking UAPs now.
為何政府要改名稱？
Why they got to change the name?
對。
Yeah.
正是如此。
Exactly.
幹，不管了。 我告訴你為什麼...
No, fuck it. I-I'll tell you why...
政府把名稱改掉了，好嗎？
they changed the name, all right?
只...只因為政府想讓我們一無所知。
It-it's 'cause they want to keep us in the dark.
記得當政府幾年前解密...
Remember when they declassified...
所有的幽浮影片嗎？
all that UFO footage a couple years ago?
是呀。 接著，民眾就開始關注這些事件。
Yeah. Well, people started paying attention.
所以政府就將名稱改為 "不明空中現象" 。
So they changed the name to UAPs.
而當沒有人搞得懂什麼是 "不明空中現象" 時，
And no one knows what the fuck a UAP is,
與論對這些事情就逐漸淡化了。
so everyone lost interest.
我看過那...那支海軍釋出的影片。
I saw that... that Navy clip.
根本沒辦法看清楚祂們。
Couldn't really see 'em, though.
應該要拍得更清楚點。
Could've been better.
那是真確的證據卻是糟糕的影片...
It's shitty footage of exact proof...
那是有外星文明...
that there's an alien civilization...
存在於宇宙間的證據。
out there in the universe.
所以，那到底是誰？
So, who's that?
老兄，少來了。 就那些大眼睛的小小人啊。
Come on, man. The little guys with the big eyes.
是嗎？ 是的。
Mm.   Yeah.
有很多不同的推論。
There's lots of theories.
要嘛祂們就是穿梭於星際間的和平旅人...
Either they're intergalactic travelers looking for peace...
不然就是未來人透過時間旅行到過去...
or futuristic humans coming back in time...
好阻止我們毀滅這顆行星，
to stop us from destroying the planet,
又或者祂們是星際殺手。
or they're fucking world killers.
行星毀滅者。
Planetary destroyers.
而這就意味著祂們已經觀察我們...
And that means that they've been fucking watching us...
和研究我們一陣子了，等待恰當時機把我們傳送到飛碟上...
and studying us, waiting for the perfect time to beam us up...
把這些金屬探針塞進我們的屁眼裡。
and shove metal probes up our fucking asses.
酷。
Cool.
無...無論如何，遠古外星人，歷史頻道。
An-Anyway, Ancient Aliens, History Channel.
記得去看。         嘿！
Watch that shit.   Hey!
嘿！
Hey!
快來！ 幫黑人姊妹個忙！
Come on! Help a nigga out!
嘿。
Hey.
哪裡可以生幾個又大又粗的幫手出來嗎？
Know where I could find me a couple of big, strong fellas?
妳還好嗎？
You good?
我沒事。
I'm good.
怎麼了？  那是什麼？
What?   What's that?
喔，這個嗎？
Oh, this?
你知道，就是，哦，我們訂的那些訓馬用具...
You know, just, uh, training horses we ordered...
我剛去領的。
that I picked up.
妳從哪裡幹的？  別管這麼多。
Where'd you get it from?   Don't worry about it.
現在，快點來幫幫我。
Now, come on, help me out.
我來。
Got you.
好了，所...所以這是什麼？
Okay, so... so what is that?
這是個誘餌？  我跟你說過。
Is it like bait?  I told you.
這只是訓馬用的誘餌。
It is a decoy for horse training.
好吧。
Okay.
該死。 慘了。
Shit. Shit.
看吧。  歐傑。
See?    OJ.
我們沒事。 我認為，他根本什麼都不知道。
We good.  I mean, he don't know shit.
喔，不。你們在做些違法的勾當。
Oh, no. You guys are doing something shady.
你們好啊！
Hey there!
嘿！
Hey!
你待在那裡不可以進來喔！
You can stay right there, though!
當然！
Sure!
在做什麼？
What's up?
我們在裝設誘餌！
We're setting up a decoy!
訓馬用的！
For horse training!
喔，這樣呀！
Oh, good!
你們知道嗎，我們也有這種東西！
You know, we got some of those!
你們從哪裡買...
Where'd you get...
你們的又是從哪裡買的？
Where'd you get yours?
這個...我不太確定！
Yeah... I'm not really sure!
我太太應該知道！
My wife would know!
好的！感謝你順道來打招呼！  回啥洨... 噓。
Okay! Thanks for stopping by!   Why the... Shh.
你又不住在這兒。
You don't live here.
抱歉。 只是想幫忙。
Sorry. Trying to help.
不用客氣！
Sure thing!
嘿。 我想要邀請你們參加我們的...
Hey. I wanted to invite you to our...
新推出的闔家歡現場秀！
new family live show!
星期五！ 下午五點！
Friday! At 5:00 p.m.!
好的！
Okay!
讚...給個讚。
Thumbs u... thumbs up.
我也該跟著做嗎？
Should I do it?
對，跟著做。
Yeah, do it.
給個讚！
Thumbs up!
就這樣，路由器已經裝設好了。
And so, the router's in the shed.
我設定攝影機 A 如果失去電力的話，
I set it up so if the power goes down on camera A,
攝影機 B 會立刻轉向天際去拍攝...
camera B's pointed at the sky to catch...
任何動靜的影像。
whatever might have taken it out.
而，哦，反之亦然，所以...
And, uh, vice versa, so...
謝謝你。
Thank you.
你們真的沒有打算告訴我...
I mean, you're really not gonna tell me...
這裡究竟發生什麼事囉？
what the fuck is going on?
你很快就會知道了。  喔。
You'll know soon enough.   Oh.
酷，神神秘秘的。
Cool, cryptic.
幹，兩個機掰人。
Fucking dicks.
如果你們需要的話，我也可以從遠端監控喔。
I can monitor the feeds remotely myself, if you want.
不需要費用。
Free of charge.
絕對不用。 不用。
Hell no.   No.
好吧，這樣的話，感謝你們。
Wham, bam, thank you, ma'am.
還有件事。
One more thing.
你們如果接到我主管打電話過來...
You'll be getting a call from my supervisor...
詢問我的服務怎樣時。
asking how my service was.
五顆星，安傑。  五顆星。
Five stars, Angel. Five stars.
謝謝你們。
Thank you.
所以，接著該怎麼辦？  我不知道。
So, what now?   I don't know.
不然妳覺得要怎麼做？  我的話...你說做什麼就做什麼。
What you want to do?   I'm... Whatever you want to do.
這樣的話，我還有些工作得完成。
Well, I got some work I got to do.
我得到外頭去...
I'm gonna go out...
我差點就上當了說。
That's a good one.
[三葉草]
我談的是今天有位婦女宣稱...
I'm talking today to women who say...
被外星人劫持至另一顆星球。
they have been abducted by aliens from another planet.
容我簡短地說，我不曉得其真實性...
May I briefly say, I don't know for a fact...
及祂們是否來自於其他星球。
that they're from another planet.
妳知道妳不在...
Well, you know you weren't
堪薩斯了吧，托托。
in Kansas anymore, Toto.
而我也沒穿著紅鞋...
And I wasn't wearing red shoes...
那雙可以喀叩作響的鞋。  對呀，對呀。
that I could click together, either.   Yeah, yeah.
不，不行。 不，我不幹了。
Nope. Mm-mm. Nope, I'm out.
我要走了。 全都去轟幹吧。
I'm going. Fuck this shit.
好吧。好吧。
Okay. Okay.
痛。
Ow.
喔，慘了！ 走開啦。
Oh, shit!  Fuck off.
把我們的東西還來。
Give us back our property.
別招惹朱比特礦場的人！ 快走。
Don't mess with Jupiter's Claim!  Come on.
怎麼了嗎？
What happened?
惡作劇的小鬼們。
The Park kids.
朱佩 的孩子。
Jupe's sons.
糟糕，他們讓 三葉草 跑掉了。
And they let Clover out, man.
啥米？ 他們敢招惹我們 海伍德？
What?  They trying to prank Haywood?
那就來吧！ 嘿。 妳幹走了人家的馬啊。
It's on!   Hey. You stole their horse.
喔。
Oh.
對呀。
Yeah.
嘿。   該死。
Hey.   Shit.
喔。
Oh.
怎麼了，尼絲？
What's up, Nessie?
沒幹啥。  就上架下架而已。
Not much. Just stocking shit.
你知道，就平時那樣子。
You know, pretty much regular.
喔，該死！
Oh, shit!
我看我得趕快洗洗睡了。
I need to take my ass to bed.
誰呀？     呦，是福來商城的 安傑。
Who this?   Yo, it's Angel from Fry's.
只是打來跟妳講，有隻蟲擋在攝影機 A 上頭。
Just calling to tell you that there is a bug on camera A.
我知道。等等，我不是跟你講過不要看我家的監控嗎。
I know. Wait, I thought I told you not to watch our shit.
有啦，我知道，我知道。
Yeah, I know, I know.
攝影機 B 失效了。
Camera B is down.
什麼？
What?
攝影機 B 失效了。
Camera B is down.
幹，就像是遠古外星人降臨了。
Like Ancient-fucking-Aliens down.
嘿！   嘿。嗨。
Hey!   Hey. Hi.
可以拜託妳把蟲從攝影機上弄走嗎，安莫洛？
Emerald, can you please get the bug off the thing?
幹，把蟲弄走啦！
Get the bug off the fucking thing!
該死。
Shit.
嗯，妳看到什麼了？
Um, what do you see?
妳有...妳有看到，像是，光束還是其它什麼的嗎？
Do you... do you see, like, lights or anything?
像是，一...一個該死的碟型物？
Like, a-a fucking saucer?
祂在雲裡。  那東西在雲朵裡。
It's in the cloud.  It's in the cloud.
歐傑！ 它在雲朵裡！
OJ! It's in the cloud!
嗯哼。
Mm-hmm.
啊，不，不，不。
Yeah, nah, nah, nah.
跑呀，歐傑！ 快跑！
Run, OJ! Run!
該死。
Shit.
哈囉？
Hello?
歐傑 怎麼了？
What happened to OJ?
沒怎樣。
It's fine.
快點。
Come on.
還好，攝影機還開著。
Okay, it's still on.
攝影機，還可以用。
The camera, it's still on.
該死，該死，該死，該死，該死。
Shit, shit, shit, shit, shit.
好了，你這隻該死的螳螂在給我祈禱啥。
Okay, you fucking praying mantis.
好吧，賤貨。
All right, bitch.
你要嚐嚐屁孩酸味軟糖嗎？
You like Sour Patch Kids?
滋味如何？
Huh?
好了，老哥。
A'ight, man.
你的行李在哪裡？ 我們走吧。
Where your shit? Let's go.
這東西一陣子沒出現了。
Haven't seen one of those in a minute.
幹它媽該死的螳螂。
Fucking praying mantis.
幹林蛤仔它最好不要再讓我遇到，
That motherfucker better pray I don't ever see him,
要是讓我遇到我就生吞它。
'cause if I do, I'm-a eat him.
我們走。  去哪？
Let's go.  Where?
天啊，我怎麼知道。
Man, I don't know.
我在艾特瓦特(加州)出了點事...
I got me a little situation in Atwater...
到現在還一直在傳訊息給我而已。
texting me back right now.
它今晚不會再出現了。  我才不管。
It's not coming again tonight.   I don't care.
不。不。
No. No.
不要。
No.
我這輩子沒見過這種東西啊，老哥。
Bro, I ain't never seen no shit like this.
這不值得。
It ain't worth it.
不，不幹。代價太高了。
No, nope. It's too much.
這樣的話妳就離開吧。
You should go, then.
反正我明天也還得早起。
I got to get up early anyway.
我還得養家活口。
I got mouths to feed.
該死。
Shit.
該死，該死，該死！
Shit, shit, shit!
你聽到了嗎？
You hear that?
幽魂 在外頭。
Ghost out there.
在那邊宣示主權。
Acting all territorial.
嗯。
Mm.
我想某些畜生就是沒辦法訓養。
I guess some animals ain't fit to be trained.
哈囉？   哦，嗨。
Hello?   Uh, hi.
嗯，請問是 安特勒斯·霍爾斯特 嗎？
Is this, uh, Antlers Holst?
是誰呀？
Who's this?
嘿，好的。我是 安莫洛·海伍德。
Hey, yeah. I'm Emerald Haywood.
嗯，我們在幾天前的一個廣告拍攝活動見過面。
Uh, we met a couple days ago at the commercial.
喔，對，牧場女孩。 記得。
Oh, yeah, horse girl. Sure.
我記得妳跟妳哥。
I remember you and your brother.
對，牧場男孩。
Yeah, horse boy.
他也在這裡。
He's here, too.
黑人騎師的後裔。  是呀。
The descendants of the jockey.   Yeah.
我想我正在跟電影圈的貴族講電話是吧。
Guess I'm talking to motion picture royalty, then.
妳怎麼會有我電話？
How'd you get the number?
我查通訊錄上的。 啊。
I got it from the call sheet.   Ah.
是這樣子，我們有個專案，然後，嗯，
So, we have a project, and, uh,
如果我跟你說這專案是個一輩子千載難逢的機會哩？
you know, what if I told you it was the offer of a lifetime?
是喔，希望不會發生在我的有生之年。
Yeah, hopefully not my lifetime.
你說得好。 嗯，我就老實跟你說了。
That's a good one. Um, I'm-a be real with you.
我們沒有大筆的預算可以先付訂金給你...
We don't have a lot of money to pay you up front...
你了解，與以往你接案的模式不同...不過，哦...
you know, not like you're used to... but, uh...
是喔。我還是習慣先收筆錢這樣我才好辦事，
Yeah. I tend to do one for them so I can do one for me,
所以要拍什麼？
so what is it?
實境節目。 喔，不。 實境節目。
Reality.   Oh, no. Reality.
紀錄片。
Documentary.
紀...紀錄片。     喔，感覺好多了。
Doc-Documentary.  Oh, that's better.
所以，我再問一次這是要拍啥？
So, again, what's it about?
是有關噩夢怎麼形成的。
It's about the shit dreams is made of, baby.
聽著，牧場女孩。
Listen, horse girl.
我有個，嗯...
I got a, uh...
超讚的檸檬蛋塔在烤箱裡...
...pretty damn superb lemon tart in the oven
我得把它準備給我那十幾個好朋友吃，所以...
I'm about to serve to ten of my closest friends, so...
別說了。
Stop.
停，停，別說了。 喔，稍等一下。 啥米？
Stop, stop, stop.  Oh, hold on one second. What?
他對這個沒興趣。  聽著，聽好，別這樣。
He's not here for that.   Look, look, no.
別裝可愛。 照計畫講。 講啊！
Don't be cute.  Stick to the plan. Say it!
我就是這樣做事。 我可沒對你的工作指手畫腳...
This is what I do. I don't go to your job
就算是玩馬屌老娘也沒有搶著做。
and knock a horse's dick out your damn hand.
哈囉？  是。
Hello?   Yeah.
是我不好。  我們現在沒事了。
Yeah, my bad. We good, man.
嗯，根據美國電影雜誌的專刊，
Um, according to American Cinema magazine,
你總能將無法電影化的題材電影化。
you make the cinematically impossible possible.
我們就是在尋找這樣的題材。
Well, we looking for the impossible shot.
這不可能。
That's impossible.
安特勒斯。
Antlers.
阿瓜•杜爾塞 這裡有東西出沒，
There's something out here in Agua Dulce,
而你也許是這個世界上唯一...
and you're probably the only person in the world...
可以將其拍成影片的人。
that can get it on film.
就...就是這樣。
Th-That's it.
牧場女孩，妳追尋的這場夢，
Horse girl, this dream you're chasing,
也許可以讓妳登上顛峰，
the one where you end up at the top of the mountain,
萬眾矚目...
all eyes on you...
也有可能是場永遠也醒不了的夢。
...it's the dream you never wake up from.
我不喜歡他。
I don't like him.
林蛤仔。 是真的。
Holy shit. It's real.
我不曉得你到底在瞎搞什麼，不過...
I don't know what you're doing here, but...
你這不是違法地...
it was illegal for you to...
監控著我們嗎。
spy on us like that.
等等，你們...你們沒發現嗎？
Wait, you... you don't know?
好了，嗯，看到的時候告訴我。
Okay, uh, tell me when you see it.
那裡。
There.
沒有移動。  正是如此。
Doesn't move.   Exactly.
很好，瞧瞧這玩意兒。
Well, look at that.
是呀。好，好，很好。
Yeah. Yeah, yeah, okay.
我回店裡後重複瀏覽這些監控片段，
I went back and scrubbed through the footage,
而那朵雲就一直在那裡...
and that cloud has been right there...
從我設定好攝影機後就沒有動過。
at least since I set the cameras up.
對呀，現在你提醒了我。
Yeah, now you mention it,
我也許也看著同一片雲朵...
I've probably been looking at the same damn cloud...
天天看了足足有六個月之久。
every day for the last six months.
該死。
Shit.
所以，我認為，祂們就在雲裡頭。
So, I mean, that's them in there.
而我們把這些記錄下來了，我們辦到了。
And we've been recording it, so we got it.
是嗎？
Right?
是呀。
Yeah.
你的"是呀"聽起來怪怪的。
Why you saying "yeah" like that?
我說，我們已經有外星人的影片證據了。 我...
I mean, we have proof of aliens on video. I...
是嗎，我可不會說這是證據。
Yeah, I wouldn't call it proof.
你認真？
Are you serious?
聽好，我之前也在網路上看過一些怪異天氣的影片。
Look, I've seen crazy weather phenomenons online before.
這不足為奇。  他說的對。
That's all I'm saying.  He's right.
影片很好，但還不夠。 還不是 歐普拉。
It's good, but it ain't it.  Ain't Oprah.
不是 歐普拉？
Ain't Oprah.
好了。所以你們覺得...
Okay. Are you guys telling me...
那裡有艘外星飛船...
that there's an alien spaceship...
就在那朵該死的雲朵裡？
in that fucking cloud right there?
祂移動的模式不像是艘飛船。
It doesn't move like a ship.
歐傑，你在說什麼？
What you mean, OJ?
如果這不是艘飛船的話？
What if it's not a ship?
[高蒂]
好了，高蒂，我們快準備好了，夥伴。
All right, Gordy, we're almost ready, buddy.
我們開始了，夥伴。 快點。
Here we go, buddy. Come on.
牠準備好了。  就定位。
He's ready.   Set.
我們開始。
Here we go.
好... 開拍。
And... action.
想當然耳我把時區設定在冰島...
And, of course, I set it to Icelandic time...
就因為我們都喜歡北極星所發散之極光，高蒂。
because we share a love of the aurora borealis, Gordy.
而妳絕對不知道現在到底是幾點。
And you have no idea how to tell time.
真棒的禮物，爸。
Great gift, Dad.
還真是能掰啊。
Way to think things through.
不知如何，你認為一個...
Somehow, you'd think that a man who can send...
能夠把火箭送上太空的人，卻只能夠...
a rocket into space would be able to manage
準備這種半吊子的生日禮物。
a halfway decent birthday present.
不!
Nope.
高蒂，妳知道嗎，考量到各個層面，
You know, Gordy, all things considered,
也許我準備的禮物並沒有那麼差。
maybe my gift isn't so bad after all.
嘿，高蒂。
Hey, Gordy.
想不到吧！ 哇哦。
Surprise!  Wow.
終於有份像樣的禮物了。
Now, that is a gift.
喔。抱歉。我的...
Oh. Sorry. My...
沒關係。 就從這繼續演吧。
That's all right.  Pick it up from there.
稍等一下。
Wait a minute.
如果我們兩個都沒辦法準備好的禮物該怎麼辦？
What happened to we both failed at finding good presents?
拆禮物吧，高蒂。 生日快樂！
Here you go, Gordy. Happy birthday.
喔，真漂亮，海莉。
Oh, beautiful, Hayley.
喔，嘿，嘿，嘿，。 不。
Whoa, hey, hey, hey. No.
不，不！蹲下！蹲下！高蒂！ 蹲下！
No, no! Down! Down! Gordy!  Down!
不。停止！  別這樣！
No. Stop!   Stop that!
喔，不。 不，不，不，不。
Oh, no. No, no, no, no.
不，不，不，不，不。不，高蒂，不！不！
No, no, no, no, no. No, Gordy, no! No!
蹲...蹲...蹲下！蹲下！蹲下！
D-D-Down! Down! Down!
你坐好！ 蹲下！
You sit! Down.
不，不，不。
No, no, no.
不，不，不！
No, no, no!
不，高蒂！
No, Gordy!
停手！ 啊！
Stop! Ah!
不！ 不！
No! No!
七人陳屍現場... 喔，我的天啊。
Seven just on scene... Oh, my God.
舒服嗎？
Feeling good?
是呀。
Yeah.
很舒服。
Feeling good.
很好。
Good.
這樣就好了。
There we go.
排練。 寶貝，再排練一次吧。
Run it. Run it one more time, babe.
好的。
Okay.
如果我跟你們說...
What if I told you...
[吉利]
呦。天氣，哦...暴風快來了。
Yo. It's, uh... Storm's coming.
我把攝影機包好以防萬一。
Just tarping up, just to be safe.
嘿，你要去哪裡？
Hey, where you going?
我去找 吉利。
I'm-a get Lucky.
好了，我們可不會讓...
Now, we're not gonna let...
幾朵烏雲毀了我們今天的樂趣，是吧，大夥們？
a few clouds kill our fun today, are we, folks?
所以，廢話少說，
So, without further ado,
歡迎蒞臨朱彼特礦場的星空牛仔特技秀！
welcome to the Jupiter's Claim Star Lasso Experience!
大夥們今天開心嗎？
How's everyone feeling today?
好的。
All right.
今天真讓人昏昏欲睡啊。
It's quite a doozy today.
哦，我想先感謝您們蒞臨現場。
Uh, I want to thank you guys for coming out here.
但首先，我們再掌聲鼓勵給...
But first, how about another round of applause...
我太太安柏。
for my Amber?
我告訴各位，這位女士可是...
I'll tell you, that woman is...
實踐我所有瘋狂想法的聖人。
a saint for putting up with all my craziness.
以及看臺上頭這些小鬼頭。
And to the knuckleheads up there.
工作人員。 歡呼吧。
The staff. Shout-out.
好了，好了。
All right, all right.
這樣夠了。
That's enough.
而我也要特別感謝...
I also want to give a special thanks to
我的初戀也是我的前同事，
an old costar of mine and my first crush,
瑪麗·喬·埃利奧特，各位！
Mary Jo Elliott, everyone!
好呀。
Yeah.
好了。
All right.
你們準備好了嗎？
You ready?
喔，別這樣。  一點勁也沒有。
Oh, come on.  That ain't nothing.
你們準備好了沒？
Are you ready?
我們開始吧。
Here we go.
你們被選中。
You're chosen.
如果我告訴你們...
What if I told you...
一個小時之後...
that in about an hour...
你們將脫胎換骨般地離開這裡。
you'll leave here different?
你們知道嗎，過去半年來的每週五，
See, every Friday for the last six months,
我和家人們不厭其煩地見證了...
my family and I have bore witness...
一個不可置否的奇觀。
to an absolute spectacle.
一個你們今天將會在這裡目睹的奇觀。
One that you'll be seeing here today.
所以讓我帶你們回到奇觀現身的第一晚。
So let me take you back to that first night.
在這裡，同一地點，
Right here in this exact spot,
我來到這裡溜頭名叫 板機 的栗色馬兒。
I'd come over to wrangle a chestnut horse named Trigger.
那時，我幾乎沒辦看見我眼前的雙手...
Now, I could barely see my hand in front of my face...
濃霧瀰漫，但我發誓...
for the fog, but I swear...
以我老婆及孩子們的性命...
on my wife and children's lives...
在晚間六點十三分；
that at 6:13 p.m.,
我看見了...
I see...
一艘碟形飛行物...
...a flying saucer
降落於迷霧之中。
descend through the mist.
老 板機 脫韁而出，直衝入峽谷。
Old Trigger took off straight into the gulch.
而，那就...
And, well...
那就像是牠只是奔向家園。
...it's like he was going home.
此刻，得把話講明白，我們看到的...
Now, just to be clear, what we saw...
是個艘飛碟。
was a flying saucer.
不可置否。
No doubt about that.
前沿些微扁平，
Slightly flatter in the front,
底部則有著圓形孔洞...
with a circular hole in the bottom...
大約兩輛校車長的直徑。
about two school bus lengths wide.
女士及先生們，我沒開你們玩笑。
Ladies and gentlemen, I kid you not.
我們正被監控著...
We are being surveilled...
被一群我稱作 "觀察者" 的外星種族。
by an alien species I call "the Viewers."
而儘管祂們尚未離開祂們的飛船現身，
And though they have yet to emerge from their ship,
我相信祂們信任我。
I believe they trust me.
如祂們不信任我，我不認為我們之中任何一人...
If they didn't, I don't think any of us...
會於此刻出現在這裡。
would be here right now.
所以，誠如我說的，在不到一小時的時間裡，
So, as I said, in just under an hour,
星空牛仔特技秀將會改變您。
Star Lasso Experience is gonna change you.
首先，我兒子們將會出場...
But first, my boys are gonna come out...
給我們一些掌聲鼓勵。 可以嗎？
and do a little number for us. Would that be all right?
快點。 快，快，快。
Hustle. Go, go, go.
好的。 我的小跟班們：
All right. My little satellites:
科爾頓、費尼斯、麥克斯。
Colton, Phoenix, Max.
記住這些名字，各位。
Remember those names, folks.
好了，我們開始吧！
All right, here we go!
那是什麼？
What is that?
你們都看到了嗎？
Do you guys see that?
哦，嗯，待在你們的座位。
Uh, uh, stay in your seats.
這真新奇。
This is new.
哦，祂們來早了。
Uh, they're early.
祂們今天準備來場真槍實彈的秀。
They're giving us a real show today.
貨真價實。  是呀。
That they are.   Yeah.
祂們今天準備來場真槍實彈的秀。
They're giving us a real show today.
祂們準備好，我們就準備好了。
They're ready, we're ready.
歡迎蒞臨星空牛仔特技秀，
Welcome to the Star Lasso Experience,
朱彼特礦場獨家演出。
only at Jupiter's Claim.
請記得避免...                 快點。
Please remember to avoid...   Come on.
使用你們的手機或任何相機閃光燈...
...using your cell phones or any flash photography...
各位，手機關機。    ...表演秀期間。
Cell phones off, y'all.   ...during the event.
快點！
Come on!
多擔待我們一點。
Bear with us now.
馴化的動物們可能還是會不受控制。
Trained animals can be unpredictable.
馬上坐下，待在你們的位置並欣賞...
Now sit back, stay in your seats and enjoy...
這場星空牛仔特技秀...
the Star Lasso Experien...
好了，男女牛仔們，
Well, cowboys and cowgirls,
是時候乘著夕陽踏上歸途了。
it's time to ride off into the sunset.
是的。 快快樂樂回家。
That's right. Happy trails.
營業時間已結束。
It's closing time.
你們不一定得回家，不過你們不能在此逗留。
You don't have to go home, but you can't stay here.
歡迎再度光臨。
Come back again.
而在這期間，我們祝您萬事順心。
And until then, we wish you well.
下次再會。 再見。
Hasta la vista. Adios.
好了，男女牛仔們，
Well, cowboys and cowgirls,
是時候乘著夕陽踏上歸途了。
it's time to ride off into the sunset.
是的。 快快樂樂回家。
That's right. Happy trails.
營業時間已結束。
It's closing time.
你們不一定得回家，不過你們不能在此逗留。
You don't have to go home, but you can't stay here.
歡迎再度光臨。
Come back again.
而在這期間...
And until then...
吉利。
Lucky.
吉利，快點，快點。 快點！
Lucky, come on, come on. Come on!
快點，快點，快點。
Come on, come on, come on.
吉利。
Lucky.
快點，快點，快點。
Come on, come on, come on.
呦。
Yo.
搞定了。
It's done.
好了，早上我會再過來把這些防護拆掉。
All right, I'll be over in the morning to tear that shit off.
或者你們可以自己拆。
Or you guys can do it yourselves.
都一樣。  不，不。
It's all the same.   No, no.
我比較喜歡你來弄。  妳當然喜歡囉。
I like when you do it.   Of course you do.
好吧，明天見。
All right. See you tomorrow.
再見。
See you.
接電話，接電話，接電話，
Pick up, pick up, pick up,
接電話，接電話，接電話，接電話。
pick up, pick up, pick up, pick up.
快點，快呀。 接電話，接電話，接電話。
Come on, come on. Pick up, pick up, pick up.
各位知道那...
Did you know that...
將照片組合...
the very first assembly of photographs...
按照順序排列成動畫...
in sequential order to make a motion picture
是一部二秒鐘黑人騎馬的短片嗎？
was a two-second clip of a Black man on a horse?
這名來自巴哈馬的騎師...
That man was a Bahamian jockey...
人稱 阿利斯泰爾·E·海伍德，
known as Alistair E. Haywood,
而他就是我的曾曾祖父。
and he was my great-great-grandfather.
嘿。  安。
Hey.   Em.
我是對的。
I was right.
那不是艘飛船。
It's not a ship.
怎麼了？
What happened?
幹，啥洨？
What the fuck?
該死。
Shit.
安，祂吞食了他們。
It ate them, Em.
祂把他們全吃了。
It ate them all.
祂是活的，安。 祂是頭野獸。
It's alive, Em. It's an animal.
祂正宣示主權，而祂覺得...
It's territorial, and it thinks
這裡是祂的領地。
that this is its home.
安！
Em!
喔，幹。
Oh, fuck.
喔，慘。
Oh, shit.
喔，這好。
Ooh, yes.
嘿，嘿。 我們有麻煩了。
Hey, hey. We're in trouble.
知道嗎？
Okay?
喔，幹。
Oh, fuck.
該死。
Shit.
什麼？
What?
幹，這啥洨？
What the fuck?
這到底是啥米洨啦？
Who the hell is that?
安！ 是誰在哀號啦？   幹。
Em! Who the hell is that?   Fuck.
在我們上面。
It's above us.
喔，該死！
Ah, shit!
該死。
Shit.
喔，慘了！ 怎麼回事啦？
Oh, shit! What the fuck?
喔，天啊。
Oh, God.
非...非常糟糕的事情正在發生。
S-Something very bad is happening.
幹。
Fuck!
是呀，我們死定了。
Yeah, we're fucked.
不。
Nope.
安。 歐傑 正趕過來。
Em. OJ's coming.
我們走。
Let's go.
得離開這棟房子。
Got to get out this house.
我得離開這棟房子。
I got to get out this house.
不，別...別...別動。 我們不能就在這裡等嗎？
No, st-st-stop. Can't we just wait, right?
你留著。   不，我才不要一個人留在這裡。
You can.   No, I'm not gonna be here alone.
我一定得離開這棟該死的房子！ 不。
I've got to get out this fucking house!   No.
就因為我們待在這裡所以我們還活著。
We're alive still because we stayed here.
跑！
Go!
快點。快點。 跑！
Come on. Come on.  Go!
快點，快點，快點，快點。
Come on, come on, come on, come on.
快點，跑快點。
Come on, come on.
跑。
Go.
好的，她...她趕得上的。
Yeah, she... she gonna make it.
歐傑。 她能夠趕上的。
OJ.    She gonna make it.
喔，嘿，小馬。  嘿，別...別瞪著他...
Oh, hey, horsie.   Hey, don't-don't look him
的眼睛看，拜託。  視效組！
in the eyes, please.   VFX!
專注眼前。 專注眼前。
Focus here. Focus here.
快點。
Come on.
走！
Go!
歡迎光臨我的酒館。
Welcome to my tavern.
我不知道你是否聽過，不過是有關於一頭野獸的事。
I don't know if you've heard, but a terrible beast is about.
牠不斷地騷擾著居民，
It's been harassing villagers,
糟蹋遺體和獵食居民的牲畜。
ruining crops and eating their livestock.
許多追求榮耀的獵人都嘗試要打敗牠，
Many a glory-seeking hunter has attempted to defeat it,
然而多數人都是自取滅亡。
and just as many have perished.
當你還在這兒...當你還在這兒...
While you're here... While you're here...
當你還在這兒時，請留意四周。
While you're here, please look around.
記者正位於加州的阿瓜•杜爾塞，
I'm here in Agua Dulce, California,
而估計約有四十名旅客及員工...
and the whereabouts of those 40 guests and employees...
於當地一家西部主題樂園失蹤，至今下落不明。
of a local Western theme park are still unknown.
當地警局全體動員...
The sheriff's office has had its hands full...
嘗試鑑識這些下落不明的旅客。
trying to identify the unaccounted for.
直至結果出爐前，只有一件事情能夠確定。
Until they do, only one thing is certain.
就是這個異乎尋常的事件...
There is something strange happening
發生在 阿瓜•杜爾塞 郡。
out here in Agua Dulce.
事件發生時，監視錄影於同時間失效。
Security cameras were off at the time.
除此之外，我們沒有，沒理由去懷疑暴力行為導致此事件。
Other than that, we have, uh, no reason to suspect foul play.
當地倒是有著規模龐大的...
We did have a considerable amount...
暴雨侵襲過境，
of rain come through here,
所以我們也不排除是山洪暴發...
so we don't want to rule out flash flooding...
導致此事件發生。 我們顯然...
as possibly having played a part. We're obviously...
點炸魚三明治的話永遠不會錯。
You never go wrong with a fried fish sandwich.
沾醬就吃得下。
Tartar got tang.
真蠢。
Stupid.
沾醬就吃得下？
"Tartar got tang"?
對吧？
Right?
如果不瞪著祂瞧的話，我不覺得祂會來吃你。
I don't think it eats you if you don't look it in the eye.
嘿，嘿！
Hey, hey!
哥，RTR。
RTR, bro.
你知道嗎？
You know?
有點像，看一下氣氛。
Like, read the room.
沒人想討論這件事。
Nobody want to talk about that.
我們走吧！ 好，好，好吧。 夠了。
Let's go!  Okay, okay, okay. Enough.
每種動物都有習性。
Every animal got rules.
對吧？ 我們知道祂想要什麼，
All right? We know what it wants,
而我們知道祂如何獵食，所以...
and we know how it comes, so...
幹。
Fuck.
我們根本就了解個屁。
We don't really know shit.
歐傑，這到底是幹嘛，老哥？
OJ, what's this about, man?
這到底是幹嘛？ 你要我...
What's this about? You want me to...
你要我說：我很抱歉？
You want me to say, "I'm sorry"?
我錯了？ 這真是蠢？
"I was wrong"? "It's dumb"?
這並不蠢。
It wasn't dumb.
這機緣很好。 停。
Own the moment.  Stop.
停，別再說了。 這很好。這很好啊。
Stop, stop this shit.   It was good. It was good.
但這個機會即將消逝。
But the moment about to pass.
而我們什麼也沒把握住。
And we don't own shit.
好了。所以，我就認定你們都會到我那邊去睡囉。
Okay. Well, I assume y'all are crashing at mine.
是的，因為你們為所欲為。
Right, 'cause you can.
因為我可不想再回去牧場...
'Cause I'm not going back...
讓那雨傘妖怪給吃了。
to the fucking monster umbrella.
還得餵飽牲口。
Got to feed 'em.
放 吉利 出來。
Let Lucky out.
一對事情要做。
There's shit to do.
老是這樣。
Always.
總是有做不完的鳥事。
Always some shit to do.
你屋頂上有臺輪椅。
There's a wheelchair on your roof.
嗨。
Hi.
那朵該死的雲一寸也沒有動過。
That cloud ain't moved a goddamn inch.
所以你們倒也不是滿嘴狗屁。
So you're not completely full of shit.
謝謝你。
Thank you.
對啊。 謝謝你。
Yeah. Thank you.
這...有外星生物...
Th-The concept of extraterrestrial animals...
在空中遊蕩已經不是新聞了。
in the sky is not a new thing.
你知道嗎，大概從五十年代左右開始...
You know, people been trying...
人們早就不斷嘗試要拍攝這些影像。
to get pictures of these things since, like, the '50s.
你知道，這可是遠古外星人...  我們要怎麼看見祂？
You know, it's an ancient...   How do we see it?
祂肚子總是會餓的。
It's gonna get hungry again.
原來。
Ah.
所以，你只要...
So, you know...
敲響開飯鐘。
just ring the dinner bell.
現在，我們知道祂不喜歡什麼。
Now, we know what it doesn't like.
那些假的馬匹及旗幟把祂搞得挺狼狽地。
That little fake horse and flags messed it up good.
會卡在祂的氣管還是什麼器官裡頭。
Got stuck in its windpipe or something.
我賭祂應該有好一陣子不會去吞那些旗幟了。
I bet it ain't gonna fuck with flags like that in a minute.
是呀。
Yeah.
我們把祂氣炸了。
We pissed him off.
我們不是祂居留於此的原因。
We're not the reason it settled down here.
朱佩 才是。
That was Jupe.
他嘗試去馴服一頭掠食者時被獵食了。
He got caught up trying to tame a predator.
我們可不能重蹈覆轍。
You can't do that.
我得與牠達成某種和睦的協議。
You got to enter an agreement with one.
是呀。
Yeah.
可以問問 齊格菲 和 羅伊。
(活躍於90年代的德裔美籍訓獸師搭檔，
2003年發生獅子攻擊事件，隔年便宣布退休)
Ask Siegfried and Roy.
好吧。
Okay.
不如問問一些當時在房子裡...
Um, asking as someone who was in the house
經歷過這些鳥事的人...  對。
when the shit went down...   Mm.
你究竟要怎麼跟這個該死的...
How exactly do you enter an agreement with a fucking...
飛碟、外星實體或管你要叫做什麼的鬼東西達成協議？
a UFO, alien entity or whatever the hell you want to call it?
牛仔外套。
Jean Jacket.
叫祂 牛仔外套。
Call him Jean Jacket.
所以，這樣如何？
So, how about this?
我們在關鍵時刻讓 牛仔外套...
How about we send ol' Jean Jacket...
進去牧場享用點小鮮馬...
some fresh horses in golden hour...
然後看看會怎樣？  不行。
and see what happens?    Mm-mm.
牧場子弟啊。
Horse people.
嗯，為何不把牠們都放走？
Mm, why not just set them free?
我們也不這麼做。
We're not doing that.
好吧。
Okay.
誰要進到牧場...
Who is gonna go down there
引這個大明星現身？
and get the star out of his trailer?
我。
Me.
我去引祂出來。
I'll get him out.
你要引到哪裡去？
Where you want it?
你把他引到這裡。
You draw him out there.
我到這邊。
I'm here.
山脊這裡。
On this ridge.
喔，真屌。
Oh, shit.
我自己客製的。
Made her myself.
純機械動力。
No electricity.
幹林蛤仔，我不是告訴過你這傢伙將會...
Didn't I tell you this motherfucker was gonna...
帶臺不用電的攝影機來嗎？
come up here with a non-electrical camera?
我們上吧，老哥！
Let's go, boy!
好呀！
Yeah!
我在祂手下已經逃過好幾回了。
I've been up under it a couple times now.
我懂祂。
I get him.
祂就是頭野獸。
It's an animal.
你不會背對一頭熊。
You don't turn your back on a bear.
你不會在鬥牛旁穿著紅衫。
You don't wear red around a bull.
祂也有習性。
It's like that.
除非你要引起祂的注意，你不會直瞪著祂。
You don't look at it unless you want its attention.
晚安，店員先生。
Good night, Mr. Storeman.
不管了。 我也到山脊(禮帽)去。
Fuck it. I call top hat.
而且我們時間也不多了。
And we ain't got a lot of time.
一天。 最多兩天。
One day. Two days, tops.
因為已經流言四起了，到時後就會...
'Cause the word is getting out, and when it does...
不好意思了，死人。  樂園閉館了。
Sorry, dead people.  Park's closed.
我們知道民眾會蜂擁而來...
...you know people gonna come
而他們總是會這麼做：
and do what they always do:
為了自身利益而去強取豪奪。
try and take it all for themselves.
好吧。
Fine.
馴場 (頂針)
Thimble.
反正這也是我一開始想要做的。
That's the one I wanted anyway.
好吧，就讓他們來吧。
Well, let 'em come.
已經無所謂了。
It ain't gonna matter.
因為我們即將做的事情...
'Cause what we about to do...
他們無法抹滅。
...they can't erase that.
祂很巨大、祂很兇殘，
He's big, he's bad,
而且祂還極具心智。
and he's got a lot of spirit.
但舉凡擁有心智的皆可被挫敗。
But anything with a spirit can get broke.
那你們就打敗祂。
So you break it.
我負責拍攝。
I'll get the shot.
嘿，嗯...
Hey, um...
我們做的是至關重要的事。
What we're doing's important.
對吧？
Right?
就像是我們所紀錄的事，這是，嗯...
Like, what we document, it's, uh...
這將會是好事，是嗎？
...it's gonna do some good, huh?
我的意思是，除了名利雙收以外，
I mean, besides the money and fucking fame,
我們還可以拯救性命。
like, we can save some lives.
幹，我們...我們甚至還能拯救地球。
Fuck, we-we can even save Earth.
是吧？
Right?
對。  是呀。
Mm.   Yeah.
♪祂們降臨地球♪
(紫色食人妖 / 謝布·伍利，1958 )
♪ Well, it came down to Earth ♪
(The Purple People Eater / Sheb Wooley,1958)
♪而祂藏於樹叢♪
♪ And it hid in a tree ♪
♪我說：紫色食人妖先生♪
♪ I said, "Mr. Purple People Eater ♪
♪別吃我♪
♪ Don't eat me" ♪
♪而祂瞧著我發出粗暴的聲響♪
♪ Well, he looked at me and in a voice so gruff ♪
♪祂說：我不會吃你♪
♪ He said, "I wouldn't eat you ♪
♪因為你太堅強♪
♪ 'Cause you're too tough" ♪
♪祂是個獨眼、獨角的...♪
♪ He was a one-eyed, one-horned ♪
♪紫色飛行食人妖♪
♪ Flyin' purple people eater ♪
♪獨眼、獨角的♪
♪ One-eyed, one-horned ♪
♪紫色飛行食人妖♪
♪ Flyin' purple people eater ♪
♪獨眼、獨角的♪
♪ One-eyed, one-horned ♪
♪紫色飛行食人妖♪
♪ Flyin' purple people eater ♪
♪對我來說就是怪模怪樣♪
♪ Sure looks strange to me. ♪
[雕像] [禮帽] [賽車] [頂針]
祂不會對你怎樣的。
He ain't gonna fuck with you.
[牛仔外套]
是時候叫醒全家人了。
Time to wake up the family.
我們上吧。
Here we go.
出來，出來，不管祢在哪裡。
Come out, come out, wherever you are.
這低能到底有沒有極限哩？
How exquisitely stupid is that?
幹林蛤仔，我們今天一定會逮到祢。
We gonna get you today, motherfucker.
霍爾斯特 的攝影機影像在哪裡啊？
Where is the feed for Holst's camera?
完畢。
Over.
不得而知。 完畢。
Couldn't figure it out. Over.
你什麼意思，你不得而知？
What you mean, you couldn't figure it out?
完畢。
Over.
哦，霍爾斯特 是用膠捲攝影機拍，
Um, Holst is shooting on a film camera,
而我們所有的攝影機都是數位的，整件事就是這樣。
and all of our cameras are digital, so it's a whole thing.
完畢。
Over.
基本上，你根本就不知道。 完畢。
Basically, you forgot about it. Over.
是喔，好吧，我這邊滿滿都是...
Yeah, well, I had my hands full...
死人車裡的電池，還得串接五十個充氣舞蹈玩偶...
rigging 50 fucking sky dancers to dead people's car batteries...
而這全部還都連結到同一個控制面板。
all connected to one control panel.
所以，是的，我幹他媽不講了。  抱歉。
So, yeah, fucking over. Sorry.
我很害怕。
I'm scared.
人員傷亡。
Man down.
人員傷亡？ 什麼？ 哪裡？
Man down? What? Where?
峽谷深處，最後一個玩偶。
Last dancer, deep in the gulch.
安，妳來看看。  我繼續拍天空。
Stay on it, Em. I'm staying up.
幹林蛤仔。
Motherfucker.
喔，等等，等等。
Oh, wait, wait.
喔，它恢復正常了。
Oh, it's back up.
也許是電池本身有瑕疵。
Could be a faulty battery.
好吧。 接著拍吧。
All right. Shot's up, then.
還沒，祂在試探。
Nah, he's poking.
這個混蛋是誰？
Who's this asshole?
身穿黑衣白色機車的人。
Man in black on a white motorcycle.
不，不，不，不，不，不。 該死。
No, no, no, no, no, no. Shit.
你有什麼事嗎？
Can I help you?
妳看見那片雲了嗎？
You see that cloud?
嘿，老兄，你什麼單位的？
Hey, man, who you with?
喔，我很抱歉。
Oh, I'm sorry.
妳是誰？
Who are you?
無名小卒。
Nobody.
對我來說妳看起來不像無名小卒。
You don't look like a nobody to me.
好了，聽著，我們正在做攝影機測試...
Yeah, look, w-we doing a camera test...
準備幫威訊通訊拍廣告片，
for a Verizon commercial,
所以我需要你離開這條道路。
so now I'm-a need you to clear the road.
這整座山谷在 GoogleMap 裡...
This whole valley comes up as blurry...
看起來就是模糊一片。
on Google Maps.
你們可真能找個荒蕪人跡的地點。
You're really tucked away back here.
朱比特礦場？
Jupiter's Claim?
如果你走另一條路的話會更快。
Quicker if you go the other way around.
是喔。
Yeah.
事實上，
Actually,
朱佩 的遊樂園和那些遊客究竟發生什麼事了？
what did happen with Jupe Park and all those people?
他可以算是妳的鄰居，對吧？
He was basically your neighbor, right?
所以，怎樣，他們消失了？
So, what, they vanished?
妳不是真的相信山洪爆發這個說法吧？
You don't believe the flood narrative, do you?
幹，各位。
Fuck, guys.
是 TMZ 八卦新聞。
It's TMZ.
喔，少來了。
Oh, fuck me.
喔，嘿，各位。 嗯，牛仔外套 肯定是在這些雲朵裡，
Uh, hey, guys. Uh, Jean Jacket is definitely in those clouds,
而祂肯定會往這裡來。
and he's definitely coming this way.
怎麼回事？ 難道妳不想上電視嗎？
What's the matter? Don't you want to be on TV?
老兄，我告訴你。
Man, I'm trying to tell you.
你絕對不想走這條路的。
You don't want to go that way.
不管了。
Fuck it.
無名小卒，這可是妳的損失。
Your loss, nobody.
我們還在拍嗎？ 完畢。
We still rolling? Over.
我們當然還在拍。
Goddamn right we are.
各位，祂來了。 完畢。
Fellas, here it comes. Over.
各位，隨堂小考。
Pop quiz, guys.
當一臺電動機車以時速一百公里的速度...
What happens when an electric bike
衝進電磁屏蔽場域會發生什麼事？
going 60 miles per hour hits an anti-electric field
會往反方向摔出去嗎？
going in the opposite direction?
該死。
Shit.
幹。
Fuck.
慘了。 我們都要去吃牢飯了。
Shit. We're all gonna go to jail.
喔，幹。 這傢伙絕對活不成了。
Oh, fuck. There's no way that that guy's alive.
啊，慘了。
Ah, shit.
該死。
Goddamn.
我就跟他說不要騎過去了。
I told his ass not to go.
我叫他不要騎過去了。
I told him not to go.
哦，嘿，歐傑，怎...
Uh, hey, OJ, what's...
幹，你要去哪裡？
Wh-Where the fuck are you going?
幹，他在幹嘛啊？
The fuck is he doing?
我要失去通訊了。 完畢。
I'm going dark. Over.
好了。不，歐傑，不。 不要！
Okay. No, OJ, no. No!
一點都不會自我保護...
No self-respecting...
嗚哦，嗚哦，嗚哦，嗚哦，嗚哦，嗚哦。
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
嘿，嘿，嘿，嘿，嘿，嘿。 冷靜，冷靜，冷靜。
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey. Easy, easy, easy.
你們的攝影機有拍到嗎？
Did you get that on camera?
看著我。看著我。看著我。  怎麼回事？
Look at me. Look at me. Look at me.   What happened?
聽著，聽著，我們...我們得救你離開這裡。
Listen, listen, we-we got to get you out of here.
看著我。  我的攝影機在那裡？
Eyes on me.   Where's my camera?
嘿！嘿！  我得拿我的攝影機。
Hey! Hey!   I need my camera.
你有看到嗎？
Do you see it?
沒了。安傑？
Okay. Angel?
什麼？ 安傑，快點。
What?  Angel, come on.
我們得裝捲新的。
We got to reload.
該死。
Shit.
等等。
Wait.
哦，你的手機在哪裡？
Uh, where's your phone?
你為什麼不拍？
Why aren't you filming this?
什麼？
What?
安傑，怎麼了？
Angel, what's happening?
好了，歐傑，如果你因為救這傢伙而掛掉的話，
Okay, OJ, if you die trying to save that guy,
我一定會宰了你。
I'll kill you.
不。不，不，拜託。
No. No, no, please.
不，拜託。 不。 我們會救你離開這裡的。 閉上你的眼睛。
Please, no. No.  We're gonna get you out. Shut your eye.
閉上你的眼睛。   等你拍完照再走。
Shut your eye.   Not before you take a picture.
先拍...拍照啦！
T-Take a picture first!
哦，填裝攝影機底片。
Uh, camera reloads.
你可以用我相機拍。
You can use my camera.
不，不行。 時間不夠了。
No, no. There's not enough time.
祂來了。
It's here.
成為魔蠍大帝。
Be Scorpion King.
讓自己功成名就。
Make a name for yourself.
那是什麼？
What is that?
是我不好，老兄。 嘿。
My bad, man.  Hey.
喔，我的天啊。
Oh, my God.
我的相機！ 我要我的相機！
My camera! I need my camera!
喔，我的天啊！ 幹！
Oh, my God! Fuck!
把蓋子給我。快蓋上蓋子。
Give me the lid. Give me the lid.
快點。 好了。
Come on. All right.
喔，天啊！
Oh, God!
喔，幹！
Oh, fuck!
真慘！ 幹！
Shit! Fuck!
嘿，嘿！ 大家都沒事吧？
Hey, hey! Is everybody okay?
敬愛的各位，說點話啊，拜託！
For the love of fuck, talk to me, please!
歐傑。
OJ.
歐傑。歐傑！
OJ. OJ!
幹林蛤仔你這個智障，最好趕快回我。
You stupid-ass motherfucker, you better answer me.
停，停，停，停。
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa,
停，停，停。
whoa, whoa, whoa.
你沒事吧？
Are you okay?
你還好嗎？ 完畢。
Are you good? Over.
喔，天啊！喔，天啊！
Oh, God! Oh, God!
喔，天啊！
Oh, God!
Oh, God.
喔，天啊！
Oh, God!
林蛤仔，我...我覺得祂吞掉了玩偶。
Holy shit, I-I think it's taking the dancers.
你有拍到這個嗎？
Are you getting this?
各位，歐傑把頭蒙起來了。
Guys, OJ's hooded up.
他要執行計畫了。歐傑 照計畫執行了！
He's doing the run. OJ's doing the run!
喔，天啊。
Oh, God.
嘿，祂離開了。
Hey, it's gone.
各位，我看不到祂的蹤跡。
I can't see it anymore, guys.
快上。快上！
Get it. Get it!
不。
No.
幹。
Fuck.
快！快！
Go! Go!
吉利，快跑。快，快，快，快，快！
Lucky, go. Go, go, go, go, go!
林蛤仔！
Holy shit!
好呀！
Yeah!
我們成功了！
Let's go!
是呀，祂就是討厭旗幟，對吧。
Yeah, he didn't like that, did he?
幹林蛤仔，歐傑 你真是個天才。
OJ, you're a motherfucking genius.
我們拍到了。我們拍到了。
We got it. We got it.
結束了。
It's over.
結束了。 各位，我們拍到了！
It's over. We got it, y'all!
當那傢伙被吞掉時...
The feed started going in and out when...
影片開始斷斷續續。
when that guy got got.
不過我們應該有用膠捲攝影機拍到吧。
But we should be covered with the film camera.
霍爾斯特，對吧？
Right, Holst?
光線。
The light.
這光，這...
The light, it's...
等等就會精美絕倫。
...gonna be magic soon.
你這是什麼意思，安特？
What you mean, Ant?
哇，不，不。 你要去哪...哪裡？
Whoa, no, no. Wh-Where you going?
安傑，一切都會沒事的。
It's gonna be all right, Angel.
我們不配拍到這份不可思議的影片。
We don't deserve the impossible.
哦，嘿，各位。
Uh, hey, guys.
霍爾斯特 剛說了些神神秘秘又毛骨悚然的話。
Holst just said some creepy, cryptic shit.
帶著他的相機。 他往山丘哪裡去了。
Took his camera. He's heading up the mountain.
完畢。
Over.
嘿，霍爾斯特。
Hey, Holst.
霍爾斯特。等等。 等一下，老兄。
Holst. Wait. Hold on, man.
跟我說話啊。 發生什麼事了？
Talk to me. What happened?
你們到底是有拍到還是沒拍到影片？ 完畢。
Did you get the shot or didn't you? Over.
這傢伙。
This nigga.
幹。
Fuck.
這太瘋狂了，是吧？
This is crazy, right?
別這樣，別這樣，別這樣。
Come on, come on, come on.
幹。
Fuck.
不，老兄。
No, man.
幹啥啦？
The fuck?
霍爾斯特。
Holst.
喔，慘了。
Oh, shit.
幹！
Fuck!
喔。
Oh.
喔，天啊。
Oh, God.
不。
No.
喔，該死。
Oh, shit.
幹。
Fuck.
什麼？
What?
痛！
Ow!
幹。
Fuck.
好吧。
Okay.
幹！
Fuck!
喔，慘了！
Oh, shit!
喔，不！
Oh, no!
別看。別看。
Don't look. Don't look.
別看。別看。別看。
Don't look. Don't look. Don't look.
別看。別看。
Don't look. Don't look.
別看。別看。別看。
Don't look. Don't look. Don't look.
去騎機車！
Get the bike!
離開這裡！
Get out of here!
喔，我的天啊。
Oh, my God.
祢死定了！ 死定了！
You're dead! Dead!
該死，該死，該死，該死。 快低頭。
Shit, shit, shit, shit. Look down.
嘿。
Hey.
快發動。
Come on.
不。
No.
喔，幹。幹。幹。
Oh, fuck. Fuck. Fuck.
不！
No!
歐傑，快離開。
Just leave, OJ.
別管了！ 快點！
Forget it! Come on!
快點！
Come on!
[警告：高壓氣體]
這一定會搞死你的。
It's gonna fuck you up.
這一定會弄死你的。
快點。
Come on.
快呀，快點！
Come on, come on!
怎麼...
What the...
快點。 快呀！
Come on. Come on!
幹林蛤仔，我一定會拍到祢。
I'm gonna get you, you motherfucker.
我要帶著照片上 歐普拉。我要帶著照片上 歐普拉。
I'm-a take you to Oprah. I'm-a take you to Oprah.
我們一起去上 歐普拉。
Let's go to Oprah.
好呀！
Yes!
幹，賤貨，沒人可以搞我們 海伍德家。
Nobody fucks with Haywood, bitch!
沒有人！
Nobody!
祢聽到沒？
You hear me?
男女牛仔們，
Cowboys and cowgirls,
是時候乘著夕陽踏上歸途了。
it's time to ride off into the sunset.
是的。 快快樂樂回家。
That's right. Happy trails.
營業時間已結束。
It's closing time.
你們不一定得回家，不過你們不能在此逗留。
You don't have to go home, but you can't stay here.
歡迎再度光臨。
Come back again.
而在這期間，我們祝您萬事順心。
Until then, we wish you well.
好了，我們進去裡面設置一下。
Okay, let's get in there and set up.
下次再會。 再見。
Hasta la vista. Adios.
好了，幫她拍張照。特寫。
Yeah, get a shot of her. Zoom in.
我們準備好了。
We're ready.
我們設置好，準備開拍了。
We're set up, ready to go.
各位觀眾，我是 沃利·帕琴科...
Folks, this is Wally Pachenko
於 阿瓜•杜爾塞 現場直播...
reporting live from Agua Dulce
在 朱比特礦場遊樂園 外頭，
just outside of Jupiter's Claim,
不久之前...
where just seconds ago
嗯，在距離這裡不遠處，發生一起莫名的爆炸...
an inexplicable occurrence, uh, just in the distance...
觀眾們也許還能聽出我語氣中的惶恐。
You can probably hear th-the shock in my voice.
哦，空中依舊瀰漫著爆炸產生的碎片...
There are still some fragments, uh, floating in the air
不知何處的不明物體...
where some-some unidentified object
就這樣飄向天際爆炸。
just drifted off into space and exploded.
嗯，觀眾們可以看到些碎片依舊從天空中落下。
Uh, you can see some fragments still falling from the sky.
哦，我們將會把一些驚人的...
Uh, we will have some amazing...